生命一号呼叫基金会控制中心
Life Foundation Control, this is LF1.
样本已采集完毕 正在返航
The specimens are secured, and we're heading home.
收到 生命一号 准备重返大气层
Roger, LF1. You are a go for reentry.
收到 启动重返大气层程序
Copy that. Initiating reentry sequence.
坐标零点四 一零三点…
Point-four by 103-point…
糟了
Oh, shit.
快关上 把它关起来
Seal it off. Seal it off!
呼叫生命一号
LF1, Mission Control.
信号不稳定 请回复
You're breaking up. Please repeat.
- 求救 求救 - 生命一号
- Mayday, Mayday - LF1!
- 求救 - 呼叫生命一号
- Mayday! - LF1, Mission Control.
请回复
Please repeat.
控制中心呼叫生命一号 请回复
LF1, Mission Control. Please repeat.
（马来西亚东）
现场整理完后才可以拿到报告 我可等不了
I don't want to have to wait for full clean-up just to get a status report.
我们已经在尽快采集现场数据了
We're collecting this data as quickly as possible.
还不够快
That's not good enough.
好的 你来告诉我到底怎么回事
Okay, maybe you can tell me what happened.
飞船上有一道裂痕
There was some kind of breach.
有一位宇航员发出了求救信号
One of the astronauts sent a distress call.
- 船上人员情况呢 - 我们还在调查
- What about the crew? - We're still investigating.
飞船坠毁在哪里了
Where did it go down?
在泗务以西二十公里处
It's 20 kilometers west of Sibu.
那至少所有的样本都找回来了吧
Did we at least retrieve all of the samples?
没有 我们只找到了其中三个
No. We have three of them.
有一个机体样本逃出了容器
One of the organisms got out of containment,
目前下落不明 我们尚不清楚是哪一个
and it's missing. We don't know which one.
她在说什么
What is she saying?
其中一个宇航员还活着
One of the astronauts is still alive.
那是詹姆森
That's Jameson.
（欢迎光临婆罗洲森林保护区）
（生命基金会）
《毒液：致命守护者》
（旧金山 加州）
- 早上好 帅哥 - 干什么
- Morning, sunshine. - What?
我醒了
I'm awake.
没打中
Missed me.
- 我醒了 - 给你
- I'm awake. - Here you go.
- 你可以把它拿回去了 - 谢谢…
- You can have it back. - Thank…
你今天穿了西装 太棒了
Oh, wow, you're wearing a suit. Yes!
- 我就喜欢你穿西装的样子 - 谢谢
- I love it when you wear the suit. - Thank you.
我今天要去参加生命基金会案子的会议
I have depositions today in the Life Foundation case.
记得给我讲讲会开得怎样
Hey, let me know how your meeting goes.
我要开会吗
My meeting?
见鬼 没错
Oh, shit. Yeah.
我今天有会
My meeting.
你的咖啡
Coffee.
- 你真好 - 谢谢
- You are perfect. - Thank you.
你还记得今天晚上有什么安排吧
Hey, you know what… You know what night it is tonight, right?
约会之夜
Date night.
所以 我大约六点左右去接你
So, I will pick you up around, uh, 6:00.
别忘了戴上你的头盔
And please do not forget your helmet.
真高兴你喜欢它
Oh, I'm glad that you like it,
我还打算在婚礼上戴着它呢
because I plan on wearing it at our wedding.
那可太性感了
That's hot.
记得喂猫
Feed the cat.
放心吧
I will.
爱你
I love you!
我也爱你 记得喂猫
Love you, too. Feed the cat.
埃迪·布洛克现场报道
Eddie Brock with boots on the ground
今天在教会区追踪一条线索…
today in the Mission District, chasing a lead into some…
大家都知道硅谷是如何管理谷歌和脸书的…
Everybody knows how our Silicon Valley overlords at Google and Facebook…
上次 我去调查了一下 问了一些让人不太舒服的问题…
Last time, I was poking around asking uncomfortable questions…
无家可归的人越来越多 已经成千上万…
Homelessness is only increasing into the thousands…
埃迪·布洛克在奥兰克市中心为大家进行报道
Eddie Brock here reporting today from downtown Oakland,
这里发生了大规模的街头示威游行
where massive demonstrations have taken over the streets.
我已经追查这起房地产贿赂案好几个星期了
I've been chasing this real-estate bribery story for a few weeks now.
你听了一定会很生气 由于全副武装…
This is gonna piss you off. …all being strong-armed…
鉴于尸体的状况
Medical examiner has yet to determine cause of death,
法医尚未确定死因
due to the condition of the body,
但你不会因为天气原因就被埋在垃圾场底部
but you don't wind up at the bottom of a landfill due to natural causes,
所以 看来这座城市
so it seems that the city
也不比凶手们更关心这些人
doesn't care about these people any more than the killer does.
我是埃迪·布洛克 这里是布洛克报道
I'm Eddie Brock, and this is The Brock Report.
嘿 理查德
Hey, Richard!
气色不错啊
Looking good!
埃迪 你不能把车停那里 哥们
Eddie, you can't park there, bro.
拜托 老兄 凡事皆可能
Come on, man. There's no such thing as can't.
你女儿怎么样了
How'd she do?
伯克利 布朗 麻省理工
Berkeley. Brown. MIT.
- 都给了她奖学金 - 我说什么来着
- She's got a scholarship, bro. - What'd I tell you?
你说什么了
You told me what?
- 凡事皆可能 - 埃迪
- No such thing as can't. - Eddie.
你的车
The bike.
麻省理工
MIT! Whoo!
你知道我最爱这片景色的哪一点吗
You know what I love about this view?
就是永远都看不腻
It never gets old.
是啊 这个嘛…
Yeah, well, uh…
我有点恐高
Height's not really my thing.
但 这次是什么任务
But, uh… What's the deal?
- 我给你找了个大人物 独家专访 - 是吗 谁
- I got you the big one, exclusive. - Yeah? Who?
卡尔顿·德雷克
Carlton Drake.
- 卡尔顿·德雷克 - 这个人很有远见
- Carlton Drake? - The man's a visionary.
他想谈谈关于火箭的事
He wants to talk about his rockets,
让大家相信火箭很安全 那场坠毁只是个意外
assure everyone they're safe, that the crash was an anomaly.
那他可真是疯了
He's… He's seriously off.
我跟你直说吧
I'm gonna level with you.
只要卡尔顿·德雷克愿意
Carlton Drake could buy us with his pocket cash,
他能用自己的零钱买下这栋楼当他的车库
turn this building into his own garage if he so wished.
现在 你只需要去问他几个关于太空项目的问题
Now, you're just gonna ask him about his space program,
感谢他一下 祝他度过愉快的一天就行了
you're gonna thank him, and you're gonna bid him a nice day.
他是个骗子
He's a crook.
埃迪 当你无家可归的时候 是我们接纳了你
Eddie, when you had nowhere to go, we gave you a home.
而现在 你知道大家有多爱看你的节目
Now, you know we love the Eddie Brock show.
你是当下最好的调查记者
There isn't a better investigative reporter working today,
但是说到底 你也只是个员工
but no one is above the network.
就当帮我个忙 埃迪 别再刨根问底了
So do me a favor, Eddie, don't start your shit again.
好吧 好吧
All right, all right.
- 就当为了我 - 好 我去就是
- For me. - All right. I'll do it.
我不知道他为什么要给我这个任务 安妮
I don't know why he gave me this assignment, Annie.
我不这么做节目
It's not… It's not what I do.
我妈妈常常对我说
Well, my mother always told me
生命中任何值得拥有的东西 都需要牺牲…
that anything in life worth having would take sacrifice…
耐心…
Patience…
还有努力的工作
And be a lot of work.
那就是你
That's you…
- 我不是 - 我就是在说你值得拥有
- That's not. - …that I'm talking about.
- 不 - 是的
- Nah. - Yeah.
遇见我是你的幸运
Well, you're lucky to have me.
老实说 我很抢手
To be fair, I'm quite a catch.
我妈是这么跟我说的
That's what my mom told me.
- 那你明天会乖乖的吗 - 不会
- Are you gonna behave yourself tomorrow? - No.
不 我要做好我的工作 这才是我要做的
No, I'm gonna do my job. That's what I'm gonna do.
我不能…不做好我的工作
I can't, you know, not do my job.
你们那个老板就是个…
The guy you work for is a complete…
我不为德雷克工作 我为我的律所工作
I don't work for Drake. I work for my firm,
我的律所为他服务
and my firm works for him.
我相信 我们律所为很多
And I'm sure that they defend many people
你认为不值得的人辩护 但我们不能重蹈覆辙
that you don't deem worthy, but we don't want a repeat.
- 重蹈覆辙 - 《环球日报》事故
- A repeat? - Of the Daily Globe incident.
你认真的吗
Really?
事故吗 那才不是事故
Incident? That's not an incident.
亲爱的 你被赶出纽约了
Baby, you were run out of New York.
- 我没有 - 我不想你再离开旧金山
- I was not. I did not. - I don't want you run out of San Francisco.
不 我在纽约还有声望呢
No, I still have currency in New York.
我是换了个地方
I was going places.
不是逃走 我去过不少地方
I wasn't running. I was going places.
事实上 我是为了你才搬到旧金山的
In fact, I moved to San Francisco for you.
- 为我吗 - 你就是我的家
- Me? - You are my home.
你一个人过也没那么糟糕 亲爱的
You're not so bad yourself, champ.
- 少说话 多吻我 - 没问题
- Less talking, more kissing. - All right.
让我先去把账结了
Let's just get the check.
我去喝点东西
I'm gonna get a drink.
（李·塔林来信）
（安妮·韦英）
（附件为审查所需的案例摘要 如果有其他需要请告知 谢谢）
（生命基金会法律备忘录）
（过失致死诉讼）
（参与第三阶段用基因疗法治疗晚期胰腺癌的实验对象为）
（萨拉·钱伯斯、菲利普·巴克利、罗伯特·麦克唐纳）
（生命基金会政策： 不上报）
很快 生命基金会将发射另一支火箭
Very soon, another Life Foundation rocket
去执行探索任务
will be sent on an exploratory mission.
由此 终有一天 也许我们都能在太空居住
And that's how, one day, we might all live in space.
很酷吧
Cool, huh?
我已经向大家展示了 我们正在做的事情
And now that I've shown you some of the cool stuff that we do here,
我希望这些能激励你们每一个人 走出去
I'm hoping I've inspired each and every one of you to go out there
并且创造出他人只能梦想之物
and create things that others have only dreamt of
德雷克先生
Mr. Drake?
没关系 别阻止她
It's okay. Don't silence her.
过来 你叫什么名字
Come here. What's your name?
阿莉
Allie.
没关系 阿莉
It's okay, Allie.
你要知道 有时人们就是会这样
You know, sometimes that's what people do.
他们总想让那些提出质疑的人闭上嘴
They try and silence those of us who ask questions.
但你知道吗 到最后
But you know what? In the end,
我们才是改变世界的人
we're the ones who change the world.
好好保管它 阿莉
Take good care of that, Allie.
大伙 这位是斯克斯博士 打个招呼吧
Guys, this is Dr. Skirth. Say hi.
嗨
Hi.
你们好 孩子们
Hello, kids.
抱歉打扰你们
Um, sorry to interrupt,
不过你该去换衣服接受采访了
but it's time to get changed for your interview.
好的 孩子们 抱歉失陪了
Yeah. Uh, kids, sorry to leave you.
阿莉 现在你说了算 来击个掌
Allie, you're in charge. High five up top.
斯克斯博士会回答阿莉和其他人的问题
Dr. Skirth will answer Allie's question, and any others.
- 下次见 孩子们 再见 - 再见
- See you next time, guys. Bye! - Bye!
你觉得呢 德雷克先生
What do you say, Mr. Drake,
我们就从头开始聊吧
we just start at the beginning?
你的父母是英国人
Born to British parents.
在十九岁的时候
And then at 19,
你发现了一种基因疗法
you discovered a gene therapy
差不多把胰腺癌患者的预期寿命延长了一倍
that literally doubles the life expectancy of pancreatic cancer patients.
实际上是延长了两倍
Well, actually, it tripled their life expectancy.
不过没关系
But it's okay.
好吧 二十四岁
Okay, um, 24.
那时还非常年轻
That's still extremely young.
你就建立了…
All right, you create
- 整个生命基金会 - 它并不是一夜之间成立的
- the Life Foundation! - It didn't happen overnight.
然后是…火箭
And then… Rockets.
你很快决定 就和所有普通人想的一样
You then decide, like any normal human being,
你要去探索太空
that you're gonna go and explore space.
你知道为什么吗 我一直都相信…
You know what it is? I have always believed…
探索太空
…that space exploration
是寻求解决地球上所有
is crucial in our quest to cure
困扰我们的问题的关键
everything that ails us here on Earth.
你想想我们在海洋和陆地上…
But if you think about everything we've found…
所发现的一切
…in the oceans and on land,
难道现在不该抬头看看吗
isn't it time to look up there?
去看看那些无法计量的待开发资源
To this plethora of untapped resources?
你的制药公司也有很多
And you have a plethora of untapped resources, also,
无法计量的待开发资源
from your pharmaceutical companies
你参与其中 它们使你意识到自己
that you're involved with, you know, to help you realize
- 有探索太空的野心 我猜 - 当然
- that ambition, I suppose. - Of course.
- 是的 - 是个循环
- Yeah. - Full circle.
那么 我要问一下 它到底是怎么运营的
So, I have to ask, how does that work,
我是说 整个生命基金会
you know, exactly, the Life Foundation thing?
它到底…到底是…
How does it… How does it, um…
我就直说吧 它是如何进行
I don't know, how does it go about,
药物试验的
say, testing pharmaceuticals?
埃迪 我们现在讨论的是火箭
Eddie, we're talking about the rocket here.
不 我不是
No, I'm not. I'm not.
我更想谈谈对贵公司的指控
I'm talking about the allegations.
抱歉 我不…
I'm sorry, I don't…
据说 您的整个商业帝国是建立在
It says that your entire empire has been built
- 尸体之上的 - 埃迪
- on dead bodies. - Eddie.
这是事实 对吧 据说你们招募
It's true, right? It says that you recruit
那些流浪汉 来做…
the most vulnerable of us to volunteer for tests…
一些往往会致命的实验
…that more often than not end up killing people.
是的 我知道网上有这样的谣言
Yeah, I'm aware of these rumors online.
- 现在外面假新闻的确太多了 - 好吧
- There's a lot of fake news out there these days. - Right.
那已经立案的那些呢
What about the legal cases?
什么
Sorry?
就是已经成案的 比如萨拉·钱伯斯
Uh, the actual legal cases, like Sarah Chambers,
- 菲尔·巴克利 罗伯特·麦克唐纳 - 够了 时间到了
- Phil Barclay, Rob MacDonald. - That's it. Time to go.
- 谢谢您来采访我 布洛克先生 - 而他们只是
- Thank you so much for coming to talk to me, Mr. Brock. - And they're just some of the people who walked
- 进了这扇门… - 祝您有愉快的一天
- through these doors… - Have a nice day.
- 请关掉摄像机 - 谢谢您
- Cut the camera off, please. - Thank you very much.
- 时间到了 走吧 - 他们就都死了…
- Time is up. Come on. - They're dead. The Dead…
- 你能带他出去吗 - 这是死亡…
- Could you show him out, please? - The Dead Found…
别碰我 这是死亡基金会
Don't touch me. The Dead Foundation thing.
- 出去 布洛克 - 我们还没聊完呢
- Get out of here, Brock. - We're not finished.
不 你完了 布洛克先生
Yes, you are, Mr. Brock.
你是在威胁我吗
Is that a threat?
祝您生活愉快
Have a nice life.
我知道你要说什么 但是…
I know what you're going to say, but…
这家伙坏透了 杰克
This guy, he is all the way bad, Jack.
- 你只要给我… - 消息哪儿来的
- If you just give… - Who's your source?
- 什么 - 你的线人是谁 埃迪
- Excuse me? - Who's your source, Eddie?
我没有线人 但我相信直觉
I don't have a source, per se. But I have a hunch.
这不是在拍《狂野西部》
This isn't the Wild Wild West.
我们不凭直觉做事
We don't go off half-cocked based on a hunch.
我们需要证据
We do the work.
需要证实我们的指控
We substantiate our accusations.
必须要有证据
We provide evidence.
你虽然很聪明 但在关键问题上非常蠢
You know, for a smart guy, you really are a dumbass.
你被解雇了 埃迪
You're fired, Eddie.
我无法再信任你
I can't trust you.
祝你生活愉快
Have a nice life.
- 一会就好 - 好的
- Will just take a second. - Okay.
嘿
Hey.
- 你这个脑子有坑的自恋狂 - 安妮
- You are pathologically self-absorbed. - Annie.
- 安妮 能先跟我谈谈吗 - 你就只想着刷存在感
- Annie, can you talk to me first? - Your ego requires constant attention,
而且固执得像头犟驴
and you're stubborn as hell.
但我愿意忍气吞声 埃迪
But I was willing to roll with it, Eddie,
因为我爱过你
because I loved you.
「爱过我」 这话是什么意思
You "loved" me? What is that supposed to mean?
你的所作所为害我丢了工作
What you did got me fired.
你利用了我
You used me.
安妮
Annie?
Annie.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
你可真美
You're beautiful.
他妈的
Damn it.
你神经病啊
Are you crazy?
你在干嘛
What are you doing?
（六个月后）
第三十六次实验
Test 36.
两种不同有机体之间
Biological interactions
发生的生物交互作用
between two different organisms.
这些生物需要和能呼吸的宿主彼此结合
These creatures need to bond with a respiratory host
以便能在富氧环境中
in order to survive for any amount of time
存活一段时间
in an oxygen-rich environment.
为什么这些宿主都会有这么剧烈的排斥反应
Well, why are all these hosts showing this hyper-acute rejection?
这正是我们想要知道的
That's what we're trying to find out.
结合过程开始了
The bonding process is starting.
正在稳定
It's equalizing.
但为什么 为什么这只兔子管用
But why? Why this rabbit?
这有点类似于器官移植
It's similar to an organ transplant.
捐献者和受赠者必须完全匹配 是吗
Where the donor and recipient must be an exact match?
没错
That's correct.
好吧 那仔细想想
Okay. So wait, think about it.
如果我们真的实现了共生
If we do achieve symbiosis,
他们就能在这里生存
they should be able to survive here,
同样的 我们也能在他们那里存活
but also we would be able to survive there.
「我们」
"We"?
开始人体试验吧
Begin human trials.
这太操之过急 怎么想都为时过早…
Oh, it's way too soon to even begin to think about something like…
斯克斯博士 你已经站在科技突破的边缘了
Dr. Skirth, you're at the forefront of a scientific breakthrough.
我希望你能勇敢点 好吗
I need you to hold your nerve. All right?
我明白
I understand,
- 但这是个伦理问题 - 想想我们的后代
- but it's an ethical question. - Think of future generations.
想想你的孩子
Think of your kids.
嘿 你的孩子还好吗
Hey, how are your kids?
开始人体试验吧
Let's begin human trials.
你做得很好
Good work.
嘿 杰克
Hey, Jack.
你有没有过这种感觉
Do you ever feel like your life
觉得自己的人生就是一团糟
is like one monumental screwup?
- 没有 - 这里是生命基金会
- Nope. - Here at the Life Foundation,
我们一直坚信…
we've always believed…
那不是你兄弟吗
Isn't that your buddy?
要吃一堑长一智
…in finding the lessons in our disappointments.
火箭坠毁之后的几个月里
In the months since our rocket failed,
我们学到了很多东西
we've learned so much.
能不能把电视关了 哥们
Do you think we could, like, switch him off?
有人还想看呢
Some people are trying to watch that.
你就这么喜欢看他吗 是吗
Oh, you are, are you? Yeah?
你不是埃迪·布洛克吗
Aren't you Eddie Brock?
我曾经是
I used to be.
我们对项目进程持相同看法
We take the same view of progress.
很激动地向大家宣布 生命基金会
Thrilled to announce that the Life Foundation
已经开始下一轮火箭发射的准备工作
has now begun preparations on its next launch.
好了 杰克 给你小费
All right, Jack, this is for you.
别一下子全花光了
I do not want you to spend it all at once.
那我要回家自娱自乐了
I'm going to go home and chase myself around the room,
假装自己是高冷单身汉
playing hard to get.
嘿 玛莉亚
Hey, Maria.
埃迪
Eddie.
最近怎么样
How's it going?
还不错 埃迪
Righteous, Eddie.
真好 报箱居然空了
Oh! Yeah, we're empty.
五美元一份
Cost you $5.
五美元买一份原本免费的报纸吗
$5 for a paper that's free?
我一路走到报箱那里
I walked all the way over to the vending machine,
把报纸拿出来 再辛辛苦苦的搬到这里
got the papers out and brought 'em back over here,
就是为了等你来拿的时候能方便一点
so you can have 'em personally delivered to you.
你是为了我才这么做的吗
You did that for me?
对 没错
Yes, I did.
五美元
Five bucks.
这可一点都不便宜
That's pretty steep.
那这样吧 你给我一美元 我给你唱首歌
Tell you what, you give me a dollar for a song,
报纸就送你
I'll throw in the paper.
要不这样吧 我给你二十美元
I'll tell you what, I will give you 20 bucks,
但别唱歌 好吗
but not to sing, all right?
成交
Deal.
谢谢
Thank you.
不客气
You're welcome.
不 你才客气了
No. You're welcome.
嗨 陈太太
Hey, Mrs. Chen.
你好吗 埃迪
How you doing, Eddie?
生活总免不了磕磕绊绊 凑合过呗
Ah, aches and pains, you know, aches and pains.
你看起来糟透了
You look like shit.
你说什么
Excuse me?
你的脸色太差了
You look like shit.
你看起来还是一如既往的漂亮
And you look as beautiful as ever.
天啊
Jesus.
精神反映肉体 埃迪
Mind is body, Eddie.
- 你最近有按我说的冥想了吗 - 没有
- Have you been meditating like I showed you? - No,
我没做 那不管用
I have not. And it does not work.
你不试试怎么就知道它没用
It doesn't work, because you don't give it a chance.
不 就是不管用
No, it doesn't work,
因为你表弟卖给我的那张DVD是中文的
because I bought a DVD off your cousin, and it was in Mandarin.
你真是笨啊
You are so stupid.
你要先听啊
You have to listen first.
你看 你刚才说的我完全听不懂
See, that right there, I don't understand what you just said.
这就是问题所在
That is the problem.
不跟你讲了
I won't tell you.
一瓶威士忌 别忘找我零钱
Bottle of whiskey, and don't forget my change.
求你了
Please.
快点
Let's go.
不然保护费就要涨价了
Before the price goes up for my protection.
一次性付清 快点
The full payment is due. Now.
把现金乖乖准备好 陈
Make sure you have my money ready, Chen.
我可不喜欢等
I don't like to wait.
生活不易啊 埃迪
Life hurts, Eddie.
就是这样
It just does.
我得走了
I gotta go.
好吧 爱你 宝贝儿
Okay. Love you, babe.
回见 宝贝儿
See you, babe.
真是个混蛋
What a dick.
（逾期未还款通知）
我都没说要去那儿工作
I'm not even asking to staff there.
我为什么要这么做 我都没法用自己的名字
Why would I do that? I can't use my name.
我可以用假名
I can use a pseudonym.
什么名字都行 你选个吧
Any name. Think… You pick a name.
我可以用女名 你看过《窈窕淑男》吗
I could be a woman. Have you seen Tootsie?
（- 嘿 老兄 你那儿有什么我可以干的活吗 - 抱歉 埃迪 我目前帮不上你）
（招聘洗碗工）
我再打给你
I'll call you back.
好的 我不会 谢谢 再见
Okay, I won't. Thank you. Bye.
（艾克哈特·托尔 《新世界：灵性的觉醒》）
要深刻认识到你所拥有的只有当下
Realize deeply that the present moment is all you ever have.
让此时此刻成为你生活的重心
Make the now the primary focus of your life.
任何行动都比无所作为强
Any action is often better than no action,
尤其是当你长时间处于低落时
especially if you have been stuck in an unhappy situation for a long time.
即使犯了错 至少你也收获了教训
If it is a mistake, at least you learned something,
不会再重蹈覆辙…
in which case it's no longer…
感谢各位的付出 使我们得以走到今天
Thank you all for bringing us to this moment.
即便我们化为尘土 我们的名字依然会被铭记
Our names will be spoken long after we are dust.
历史始于今日
History starts now.
这是第一天
This is day one.
第一次结合即将开始
This is first contact.
我们开工吧
Let's get to work.
正在建立实验体监测基线
Establishing subject baseline.
所有生命体征显示正常
All vital signs are normal.
给我接通一下
Put me through.
不用害怕 以撒
There's no need to be frightened, Isaac.
没必要
There's no need.
以撒
Isaac.
你知道这个名字来源于《圣经》吗
You know that's a biblical name?
知道 先生
Yes, sir.
上帝曾对亚伯拉罕说“把你的儿子献给我
God said to Abraham, "Give me your son,
“向我证明 你愿意牺牲
"show me you are willing to sacrifice the one thing
“对你来说最宝贵的东西” 他做到了
"most precious to you, " and Abraham was willing.
你知道这个故事最打动我的是什么吗
You know what's always impressed me about that story?
这不是亚伯拉罕的牺牲 而是以撒的牺牲
It isn't Abraham's sacrifice. It's Isaac's.
我不懂上帝为何会提出这种残酷的要求
Now, I don't know what kind of God would ask that of someone,
但我的想法始终没变
but it doesn't change anything for me.
以撒一直是这个故事里的英雄
Isaac is still the hero of this story.
看看你周围 看看这个世界
Look around you. Look at the world.
你看到了什么 战争 贫穷
What do you see? War, poverty,
这颗星球已经到了崩溃的边缘
a planet on the brink of collapse.
在我看来 上帝已经抛弃了我们
I would argue that God has abandoned us.
他没有信守承诺 以撒
He didn't keep his end of the bargain, Isaac,
所以现在轮到你我来做点什么让一切回归正轨
so now it's down to you and me to put this right.
而这一次 以撒 我们能行
And this time, Isaac, we can.
我们会成功的
We will.
这一次 我不会抛弃大家
This time, I will not abandon us.
好的
Yes.
打开
Open it.
那是什么鬼东西 什么 不…
What the hell is that? What? No, what…
求求你让我… 不
Please let me… No.
求你了 求你了
Oh, please, please, please!
他的生命体征很平稳
His vitals are holding steady.
- 它去哪儿了 - 不可思议
- Where the hell did it go? - Incredible.
它去哪儿了
Where did it go?
它在哪儿
Where is it?
带下个志愿者过来
Bring in the next volunteer.
我以前是做记者的
You know, I used to be a reporter.
而且…
I was…
而且还是一个挺成功的记者 你知道吗
I was pretty successful, as well, you know?
这个工作经常需要我…
My job, it required you to…
你懂的 去跟踪别人
You know, to follow people
就是那些不想被跟踪的人
that did not want to be followed
还有就是隐藏自己
and hide in plain sight.
我是说…
I mean…
这种跟踪最讲究不露痕迹
You have to know how to disappear.
当年我最在行了 但是你…
I was pretty good, but, you know, you…
不管你是谁 你的跟踪技术都很烂
Whoever you are, you suck.
好吧
Okay.
我叫朵拉·斯克斯
Uh, my name is Dora Skirth.
我需要你的帮助
I need your help.
- 我在生命基金会工作 - 是吗
- I work at the Life Foundation. - You do?
- 是的 - 好工作
- Yes. - Wow. Good for you.
再见
We're done.
别…
No…
布洛克先生 拜托了 请听我说
Mr. Brock, please… Please listen to me.
你对他的所有控诉
Everything that you accused him of,
都是对的 一切都是真的
you were right. It's all true.
- 我已经不在乎了 - 真的吗
- I don't care anymore. - Really?
但德雷克的实验室里招募了很多流浪汉
Because he's got a lab filled with poor people,
而且他们都签署了自己根本看不懂的弃权声明
and they're all signing waivers that they don't understand,
他把他们当成实验用的小白鼠一样
and he's using them like guinea pigs,
他们就快死了
and they are dying.
他们都快死了
They are all dying.
- 你亲眼看到了吗 - 是的
- You've seen that? - Yes.
过来
Come here.
我凭什么相信你
Why would I believe you?
因为这是真的
Because it's true.
我以前相信他 而且我…
I believed in him, and I…
我告诉自己这一切都是值得的
I told myself that it was worth it
因为我们是在治愈癌症 但这次的实验不一样
because we were curing cancer, but now this is different.
- 有些事情变了 - 去报警吧
- Something else. - Go to the cops.
我不能报警
I can't do that.
我担心他会伤害我的家人
I'm afraid of what will happen to my family.
- 他是个非常危险的人 而且权力很大 - 我知道
- He's a very dangerous man, and he's a very powerful man… - I know,
我知道他有多危险
I know how dangerous he is,
因为我第一次采访他之后
because the very first time I interviewed him,
就那一次 第二天我就丢了工作
just once, I lose my job the very next day.
事业没了 女朋友没了
I lost my career, I lost my relationship,
房子也没了 我失去了我所在乎的一切
I lost my apartment, I lost everything I ever cared about.
你知道为什么吗
You know why?
卡尔顿·德雷克毁了我 一切都完了
Carlton Drake ruined me. Finished.
现在 如果真如你所说
Now, if you are who you say you are,
千真万确的话 而且你有证据
genuinely, and you have proof,
那你应该非常 非常 非常害怕
then you should be very, very, very afraid.
我是很害怕
I am.
你得另请高明了 斯克斯小姐
You need to find yourself another white knight, Ms. Skirth,
因为我受够了
because I am done.
我受够了这些鬼话
I am done with all of this shit.
什么鬼话
What shit?
所有这些「拯救你的同胞」这种鬼话
All of this "saving my fellow man" shit.
明白了吗 晚安
All right? Good night.
埃迪
Eddie?
嗨
Well, hey.
安妮 我只是刚好路过 然后…
Anne, I was just walking by, and, uh…
我看到了贝尔韦德尔先生
I saw Mr. Belvedere.
我挂念他过的怎么样 所以…
I felt concerned for his welfare, so…
埃迪…
Eddie…
这位是丹
This is Dan.
- 丹 这是埃迪 - 是吗
- Dan, this is Eddie. - Yeah.
- 嗨 - 嗨 伙计
- Hey. - Hey, man.
安妮经常提起你
Annie's told me a lot about you.
- 是吗 - 对
- Really? - Yeah.
我很钦佩你的工作
I'm a big fan of your work.
- 谢谢 - 真的吗
- Thank you. - Really?
很酷的工作 他扳倒了很多人
It's pretty cool, all the people that he took down.
是啊 我就是其中之一
Yeah, I was one of them.
这样吧 你们先聊
Well, look, I'll let you guys catch up.
- 我进屋等你 - 你最好了
- So I'll see you inside? - You're the best.
- 很高兴见到你 哥们 - 我也是
- Really nice meeting you, man. - Uh, you, too.
他有你家的钥匙 你知道这事吗
He has a key. You know he has a key?
知道 不然他怎么进屋
Yeah. How else would he get in?
也是 好吧…
Yeah. Well, uh…
所以 你最近怎么样
So, uh, what you up to?
你知道这跟你完全没关系 对吧
You realize that's light-years away from being any of your business, right?
嘿 我只是随便问问
Hey, well, just asking, you know.
这位 丹 他是个律师吗
So, is Dan, uh, a lawyer?
不 他是医生
No, he's a doctor.
准确来说是外科医生
Surgeon, actually.
贝尔韦德尔先生怎么样
How's Mr. Belvedere, anyway?
我很想说它很想你
I would say that he misses you,
但那也太假了 因为…
but that would be bullshit, because…
- 它只是只猫 - 不 因为它从来都不喜欢你
- He's a cat. - No, because he never liked you.
不 它是猫 猫谁都不喜欢
No, he's a cat, and cats don't like anyone.
你看起来挺好的 你最近好吗
You look good, by the way. You doing good?
你来这儿干什么 埃迪
What are you doing here, Eddie?
我来这里是因为我想你了
I'm here because I miss you.
非常想
A lot.
我们本来都要结婚了
You know, we were gonna get married.
就在不久之前 但现在…
That wasn't so long ago, and now, you know…
我都不敢相信我们分开了
I can't really believe that we're not…
我们还能重新开始吗
Are we gonna try and find our way back?
不 不可能了
No, we can't.
是你自作自受 埃迪
You did this, Eddie.
不怪卡尔顿·德雷克 也不怪电视台
Not Carlton Drake, not the network.
怪你
You.
（朵拉·斯克斯博士）
你好 这里是斯克斯博士
Uh, hello. This is Dr. Skirth.
我是埃迪·布洛克
Yes, Eddie Brock here.
我们得谈谈
Talk to me.
你确定这样能行吗
Are you sure this is gonna work?
趴下 别说话就行了
Just stay down and shut up, please.
53.5 上方909RPM
53.5, win-909 RPM.
地球的人口过剩和气候变化
Overpopulation and climate change.
这两件事德雷克也没法控制
These are two things that Drake cannot control.
好 明白了
Yeah, got it, right.
再过一代 地球就不再适合我们人类居住了
We are literally a generation away from an uninhabitable Earth.
- 对 - 德雷克想用他的私人火箭
- Uh, yeah. - Drake is using his personal rockets
来搜寻宜居之所
to scout real estate.
这故事挺有意思的
You know, it's a really interesting story,
但我们还是直接跳到他杀人的那部分吧
but we need to just get to the part where he's killing people.
德雷克派了一艘飞船去执行搜寻任务
Drake sent a ship on a recon mission.
返程的时候 他们发现了一颗彗星
On the way back, they found a comet.
一颗彗星
A comet?
船载计算机显示那里有生命迹象 有成千上万个生物体
Onboard computers indicated the presence of life, of millions of organisms.
等等 等等 你说有成千上万个生物体
Wait, wait, wait, when you say "millions of organisms, "
- 什么意思 - 我们带回来了一些样本
- what do you mean? - We brought back some specimens.
你是说外星人吗
You're talking about aliens?
那种…外星人
Like, aliens?
E.T。要给家里打电话
E.T. phone home.
外星人
Aliens, yeah.
没错
Yes.
但我们不这么叫它
But we don't call them that.
- 我们称它为共生体 - 共生体
- We call them Symbiotes. - Symbiotes?
他们无法在我们的环境中独立生存
And they cannot survive in our environment without help.
德雷克认为 人类与共生体的结合
Drake believes that the union between human and Symbiote
是我们存活的关键 但不是在地球上
is the key to our survival, but not here on Earth.
德雷克想把人类和外星人结合起来
Drake is trying to put human beings and aliens together?
就是为了能在太空生活
So they can live in space?
我们称这种人类为宿主
We call them hosts.
真是太疯狂了 对吧 他简直就是个疯子
That's nuts, isn't it? That's completely insane.
没错 这事根本没有试验方案
Yes. There's no protocol for this thing.
他就是强行匹配
He's just feeding them in.
如果匹配失败…
If the match isn't exact…
电梯巡逻检查
Elevators patrol check.
快进去 别碰任何东西
Please, just go in. Don't touch anything.
- 我不会的 - 快走 我来应付他
- I won't. I won't. - Go, go, go. I'll take care of him.
斯克斯博士
Dr. Skirth.
我以为你们都回家了
I thought you'd all gone home.
是啊 不过 你懂的
Oh, yes. Well, you know what they say.
科学不知疲倦
Science never sleeps.
（状态稳定 已寄生四天）
- 埃迪 是我 放我出去 - 玛莉亚
- Eddie! It's me. Let me out! - Maria? Maria?
- 拜托了 快让我出去 - 我不知道怎么让你出来
- Please! Let me out! - I don't know how to get you…
- 快让我出去 快 - 我不知道怎么做
- Let me out. Out. - I don't know how.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
天啊 玛莉亚 住手 玛莉亚
Oh, God! Maria, no! Maria!
玛莉亚 别 玛莉亚 住手
Maria! No, Maria, no!
第三区实验室出现安全漏洞
There has been a security breach in Lab Sector 3.
不 玛莉亚
Oh, no. Maria?
玛莉亚
Maria!
该死
Oh, shit.
重复 这是银色级别安全漏洞
Repeat, this is a Code Silver security breach.
所有安保人员 请迅速前往第三区实验室
All security personnel, please respond to Lab Sector 3.
不许动
Freeze!
（警告 禁区）
发现目标
Got eyes on!
追
Go!
追 快追
Go! Go!
他跑哪儿去了
Where the hell'd he go?
- 我没看到他 - 分头找
- I'm not seeing him. - Fan out.
- 找到他 - 没有 还没找到
- Find him. - Nothing. Nothing yet.
第四搜索队 第四搜索队
Search Team 4, Search Team 4.
往东二百英尺去追
Backtrack 200 feet east.
我是朵拉 请留言
This is Dora. Leave a message.
斯克斯 是我 我刚到家
Skirth, yeah, it's me. I just got back.
你还好吗 你没联系我
Are you all right? I haven't heard from you,
我想知道你现在情况如何
so I want to know if you're all right.
不过没错 实验室里的事真是个猛料
But, yeah, that was a great call on the lab.
你是对的
You're absolutely right.
对 听着
Yeah. Listen.
我有个线人
I got a… I got a guy.
我现在准备打电话给他 然后…
I'm gonna call him and, uh…
我拍了好多的照片
Oh, I got a bunch of photographs.
他说会刊登这些照片 但是我需要你跟我一起过去
He will publish those photographs, but I need you to come with me.
回个电话给我 别忘了
Uh, could you just call me back? Call me back.
太棒了
Yeah.
我这是怎么了
What is wrong with me?
埃迪
Eddie.
有多严重
How bad?
非常糟
It's bad.
说具体点儿
How bad?
入侵者把共生体带走了
Well, we assume the intruder took it.
带走了 带走了
Took it? Took it?
我们都不知道发生了什么
We don't know what happened.
我要和昨晚值班的每一个人谈话
I want to speak to every man who was on duty last night.
- 已经谈过了 先生 - 但是我还没谈
- Already did, sir. - But I didn't.
赶紧把尸体给我移走
Get it out of my sight.
- 卡尔顿 你得看看这个 - 又怎么了
- Carlton, you need to see this. - What now?
他的血压恢复到正常值了
His blood pressure's back to normal.
肝功能也正常了
Liver functions, too.
我就知道
I knew it.
他的身体只是需要时间来适应
See, his body just needed time to adjust.
没时间可浪费了 马上扩大试验规模
I don't want to waste any more time. I want to up the tests.
- 好吗 - 好的
- Okay? - Yeah.
走吧
Come on.
你被解雇了
You're fired.
把我的共生体找回来
Find my Symbiote.
马上
Now!
天啊
Jesus.
请注意 乘坐2517次航班
Attention, passengers for Flight 2517
经香港飞往旧金山的乘客
to San Francisco via Hong Kong.
十五分钟后在九号登机口登机
We will be boarding at gate 9 in 15 minutes.
请出示登机牌
Please have your boarding passes…
苏茜 过来 在这边
Suzy. Come on, over here.
麻烦找一下安妮·韦英
May I speak to Annie Weying, please?
你能告诉她有急事吗
Can you tell her that it's an emergency?
食物
Food.
谁在说话
Who said that?
不 我不是跟你说的
No, I'm not talking to you.
你能告诉我她在哪吗
Can you please tell me where she is?
太好了 谢谢
Great. Thank you.
（- 发生什么了 回我电话 - 我没事 待会打给你 注意安全）
好的
Okay…
是的 拉娜 两人用餐吗
Yes, Lana for two?
- 不好意思 先生 - 行了 知道了
- I'm sorry, sir? - Yeah. Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- 先生 - 太好了
- Sir? - Oh, yes.
- 天啊 埃迪 你怎么在这 - 安妮…
- Oh, my God, Eddie. What are you doing here? - Annie…
- 不不不… - 不是 我有些事得告诉你
- No, no, no… - No, I have to tell you something.
- 不不不 求你了 - 不 我必须现在说
- No, no, no. Please. - No, now. I have to.
我打听到你在这 你是我唯一信任的人
Work told me you were here. You're the only person that I trust.
- 你喝醉了吗 - 对
- Are you drunk? - Yeah.
- 没有 我闯进了生命基金会 - 埃迪
- No, I broke into the Life Foundation. - Eddie,
- 你干了什么 - 是啊 但我可能…
- you did what? - Yeah, but I may…
我觉得我可能被感染了
I think I may have been infected.
- 他在发烧 你体温很高 - 埃迪 你看起来不太好
- He's burning up. You're really hot. - Eddie, you look like you're in a bad way.
是啊 我确实不太好
I am. I am in a bad way.
埃迪 天啊
Eddie, Jesus!
这个不新鲜
This is dead.
死的
Dead.
埃迪 快坐下
Eddie, sit down.
好的 没问题 好了
Okay, all right. Okay.
- 埃迪 埃迪 - 够了 别这样
- Hey, hey, Eddie, Eddie, Eddie. - Stop that.
- 先生 对不起 - 埃迪 快停下来
- Sir, sir, sir, I'm so sorry. - Eddie, quit it.
快放下 埃迪
Put it down. Eddie!
清醒点儿
Snap out of it!
不
No.
好吧 这个不好吃
All right. It's no good.
鲍比 你没事吧
Bobby, are you all right?
嘿 等下
Hey, hey, hey.
我是医生 我是医生
I'm a doctor. I'm a doctor.
我好热啊 大家都不热吗
I'm hot. Is anyone else hot?
你受伤了吗
Are you hurt?
- 先生 对不起 - 不 闭嘴
- Sir, excuse me. - No! Shh!
等等 你要去哪儿 埃迪
Wait, where are you going? Eddie?
太过分了 我要报警
This is unacceptable. I'm gonna call the police.
你在干什么 不 求你别这样
What are you doing? No, please don't.
- 不 - 埃迪 求你了
- No. - Eddie, please.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
- 我现在必须报警了 - 不 请别报警
- Now I'm gonna call the police. - No, no. Please don't call the police.
快叫救护车 我是医生 他是我的…
Here, call an ambulance. I'm a doctor. This man is my, um…
病人
Patient.
感觉好多了
Oh, it's much better.
你疯了吗
You are insane.
- 他在杀人 - 谁在杀人
- He's killing people. - Who's killing people?
卡尔顿·德雷克
Carlton Drake.
- 天啊 埃迪 别来这套 - 是的 就是他
- Oh, God, Eddie not this again. - Yes, he is. He is!
我有证据
And I have proof!
嘿 埃迪…
Hey, Eddie…
埃迪
Eddie.
Eddie?
埃迪 能听到吗
Eddie, can you hear me?
是我 丹
This is Dan speaking to you.
嘿 丹
Hey, Dan.
- 你终于醒了 - 我这是在哪
- Welcome back. - Where am I?
你在核磁共振室
Uh, you're in the MRI.
我们给你注射了点的镇静剂
Okay, we've given you a little sedative.
- 安妮在哪儿 - 她现在不在这
- Where is Anne? - Anne is not here right now.
我们要给你做些检查 好吗
We're gonna run some tests, okay?
不会有任何痛苦
It's gonna be completely painless.
所以 你只要安静的躺着就好
So, you know, just try to stay still.
放松 然后…
Uh, relax, and, um…
好的 开始了
Yeah, here we go.
埃迪 你怎么了
Eddie, what's happening in there?
埃迪 你还好吗
Eddie, you okay?
快关掉
Shut it down.
你没事了
You're okay. Yeah.
出来 你还好吧
Coming out. You all right?
- 还好 - 看着我 看着我
- Yeah. - Here, look at me, look at me.
- 你没事吧 - 没事
- You okay? - Yeah.
- 好的 - 深呼吸 好吗 你没事的
- All right. - Just take a deep breath. Okay? You're okay.
好的
Yeah.
听着 害怕检查的人不止你一个
Now, listen, you're not the first person to freak out in there.
我也有幽闭恐怖症
I get claustrophobic, too.
路易斯医生
Dr. Lewis?
- 天啊 - 嘿 曼弗雷迪女士 你还好吗
- Oh, boy. - Hey, Mrs. Manfredi. How are you?
我刚看见莫里斯了
Oh, I just saw Morris.
他又在那里不停地发牢骚 像个老小孩似的
And he's whining and complaining like an old baby again.
- 真想不到 - 非常感谢你
- Oh, good. - Oh, thank you so much.
没事 我的荣幸
Yeah, my pleasure.
好了 曼弗雷迪女士 我们已经说过狗的问题了
Okay, Mrs. Manfredi, we talked about the dog.
我喜欢狗 但是你不能在医院养它
Okay, love the dog. You can't have the dog.
抱歉 杰米尼 别叫了
Sorry. Gemini.
我们会把你的病情彻底查清 好吗 我向你保证
We're gonna get to the bottom of this. All right? That I can promise you.
但现在你还是回家休息一下吧
But for now, go home, get some rest.
检查结果出来我再打给你 好吗
I'll call you when your tests are in. Okay?
- 好的 谢谢你 - 没事
- All right, thank you. - Yep.
- 谢谢你 丹 谢谢你 - 不用客气
- Thank you, Dan. Thank you. - You got it.
- 你好 博士 - 你好
- Hello, Doctor. - Hi.
你那边也是相同的反应吗
Did you have the same reactions
不用考虑温度问题…
regardless of the temperature…
下午好 斯克斯博士
Good afternoon, Dr. Skirth.
共生体和宿主已经合为一体
The creature and the host are one.
一切都很正常
Everything was fine.
那为什么宿主的身体还是会越来越衰弱
So, why does the human continue to waste away?
我不知道 给他注入的营养液喂大象都够了
I don't know. We've given him enough liquid nutrition to feed an elephant.
但共生体完全没影响吗
But the organism is unaffected?
- 共生体生命力很健壮 - 那就好
- The Symbiote is thriving. - Good.
但问题还在于 共生体在逐渐蚕食宿主
But once again, it's killing the host.
它让宿主的器官衰竭
It's consuming his organs.
看看这个
Oh, watch this.
你在干什么 他伤到它了 快住手
Whoa, whoa, what are you doing? You're hurting it. Stop it!
四千至六千赫兹的声音会对它造成很大的伤害
Sounds in the 4, 000 to 6, 000 hertz range are very harmful for it.
- 那就别弄出这样的声音 - 好的
- Well, then don't make those sounds. - Okay.
他之前一直很稳定 到底发生了什么
He was stabilizing. What happened?
他马上就要急性肝衰竭了
He's approaching acute liver failure.
我们需要再找一个宿主
We're gonna need another host.
设计得太差了
Such poor design.
你说什么
Excuse me?
我说人类
Human beings.
抱歉 打断你们一下
Sorry to interrupt.
你可能需要些好消息
Thought you'd like some good news.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
饿了
Hungry!
该死的
Oh, goddamn.
我没事 不用担心我
I'm okay. Don't worry about me.
能借过一下吗 不好意思
Can I get through, please? Excuse me.
谢谢
Thank you.
我就站在这里 好吗
I'm just gonna stay here, all right?
等这辆电车停下
Until the cable car stops.
都没事儿 好吧
We're good. All right.
谢谢
Thank you.
借过
Excuse me.
嘿 安妮
Oh, hey, Anne.
埃迪 嗨 你感觉怎么样
Eddie, hi. How you feeling?
我感觉 我是病了
Oh, feeling… I'm sick.
好吧 埃迪
Well, Eddie,
你感染了寄生虫
you have a parasite.
他们还不确定它的来源
They're not exactly sure how you got it,
但这可以解释你为什么发烧了
but it would explain the fever.
这就说得通了
That would make sense.
还有 我一直能听到一个声音
Also, I'm hearing, uh, a voice.
幻听实际上十分常见
Auditory hallucinations are actually very common.
嘿 丹 你好吗
Oh, hey, Dan. How you doing?
我不知道你也在听电话
I didn't realize that you were on the call, too.
对 我在
Yeah, I'm here.
丹 这个寄生虫…
Hey, Dan, would this parasite…
它能够让我 我不知道该怎么说
Would it, like, be able to make me, I don't know…
比如 它能够让我爬上一棵很高很高的树
Like, climb a really, really, really tall tree,
而且速度非常非常快吗
but super, super fast?
没错 我们刚刚就这么做了
Yes. We just did.
埃迪 这可能是因为
Uh, well, Eddie, it sounds like
你的新陈代谢不太正常
it might be causing some metabolic abnormalities
所以你的体液环境也不太平衡
that are making it hard for your body to maintain homeostasis.
你刚说什么「代谢」、「体液」 我听不明白
You said "causing" and "body, " and… I lost you.
听着 埃迪 我们会给你一些药物
Listen, Eddie, um, we are gonna get you on some meds,
将你体内的寄生虫清理出去
and we are gonna clear that out.
- 好的 - 这是不可能的
- Yes. - Never gonna happen.
你能不能别这样 现在不是时候
Will you stop doing that now. Not now.
- 埃迪 我们只是想帮你 - 我知道
- Eddie, we're just trying to help you. - I know.
我知道 我刚刚不是在和你说话 安妮
I know. I'm just, I'm not actually talking to you, Annie.
那你在跟谁说话
Who are you talking to?
我等会儿再打给你 好吗
I'm just gonna call you back, all right?
谢谢 谢谢 丹 谢谢你们俩
Thank you. Thank you, Dan. Thank you. Thank you, both.
怎么了
Yeah?
嘿 你能把音乐声关小点吗
Hey, can you turn your music down, please?
因为我现在真的很难受
'Cause I'm having a really hard time.
管你呢
Whatever.
好 哥们 没问题
Yeah, sure, man. Yeah.
- 我马上把声音调小 抱歉 - 谢谢 谢谢
- I'll just turn it right down. Sorry. - Thank you. Thank you.
对于我们现在所做的事情
I was troubled by
我感到很不安
what we've been doing.
我知道
I get it.
我明白
我们都有感到不安的时候
We've all been troubled.
这是人的正常反应
It's the nature of what we do.
但你需要告诉我 昨天谁和你一起来的
But I need you to tell me who was here with you.
我需要你告诉我
I need that from you.
我不能告诉你
I can't do that.
只有找到了你的那位朋友 我们的研究
We can't fix things unless we begin with
才能继续
your friend.
只有找到他 才能帮他
The person who was here.
因为他会死的 他现在很危险
Because they're gonna die. They're in great danger.
你明白的 对吗
You know that, right?
只有找到他 把他们带回来
They're gonna die unless we bring them back here,
你才能帮助他和共生体活下来
where you can help to keep them alive.
嘿 朵拉
Hey. Dora.
我保证 从今以后 我们会改变实验方式
I promise, from here on in, we will do things differently.
你能相信我吗
Will you trust me?
埃迪·布洛克
Eddie Brock.
Eddie Brock?
你曾是我们最好的研究员
You were our best.
打开
Open it.
不 不
No! No!
不 不 不要
No! No! No!
不要开门
Do not open that door.
别动
Stay put.
- 嘿 埃迪 - 这家伙是谁
- Hey, Eddie. - Who the hell is this guy?
我来取回德雷克先生的东西
I'm gonna need Mr. Drake's property back.
你在干吗
What are you doing?
我…
I'm, uh…
我要把手举起来了
I'm putting my hands up.
你让我们看起来很怂
You are making us look bad.
我…不 我没有
I… No, I am not.
你有
Yes, you are.
- 不 我没有 - 明明有
- No, I'm not. - Yes, you are!
- 不 我没有 - 你为什么要这么做
- No, I'm not. - Why would you do that?
因为这时候就应该举手
'Cause it is a very sensible thing to do.
- 埃迪… - 那我就自己来处理了
- Eddie… - I will take care of this myself.
- 什么 - 埃迪 东西在哪
- What? - Eddie, where's the bug?
把他拿下
Take him down.
很抱歉伤害了你的朋友们
I'm so sorry about your friends.
- 这是什么东西 - 应该问「是谁」
- What is that? - Not "what." Who.
该死
Shit.
非常好
Outstanding.
现在让我们咬下他们的头 然后把他们堆在角落里
Now let's bite all their heads off and pile them up in the corner.
我们为什么要这么做
Why would we do that?
那边堆身体 这边堆头
Pile of bodies, pile of heads.
什么鬼东西 伙计
What the shit, man
不 不 不
No! No, no, no!
- 什么鬼 - 老兄 你是怎么做到的
- What the hell? - Dude! How did you do that?
很显然 我有寄生虫
Apparently, I have a parasite.
德雷克先生 目标带着共生体跑了
Mr. Drake, our subject is carrying the Symbiote.
现在给您传输刚才的画面
Connecting you to the feed now.
他和共生体成功结合了
He's achieved symbiosis.
看到了吗
Are you seeing this?
你们看到了吗 他竟然成功了
Are you seeing this? He's achieved symbiosis!
特里斯…
Treece…
特里斯 把我的新物种带回来
Treece, bring me back my creature.
埃迪
Eddie.
你没在里面 对吧 我只是产生了幻觉
You're not even here, are you? I'm just seeing things.
这不是真的 你只是我的幻想
It's not real. You're in my head.
因为你只不过是个寄生虫
'Cause you're just a parasite.
「寄生虫」
"Parasite"?
你这是得脑瘤了 埃迪
You have a brain tumor, Eddie.
我找到他了 在舒勒大楼后面的小巷里
I got him. He's in the alley behind the Schueller Building.
我很抱歉把你叫做寄生虫
I am sorry that I called you a parasite.
我也愿意和你平等地交流
We can discuss this like two men.
这是什么 是什么
What is that? What is that?
什么
What?
别让他跑了 明白我的意思吗 特里斯
Do not let him get away. Do you understand me, Treece?
收到 武器已经准备好了
Copy. Weapons are armed and ready.
出动无人机
Launch the drones.
低头
Duck.
- 谢了 - 不客气
- Thank you. - You are welcome.
这简直难以置信
This is beyond anything we thought was possible.
天啊 不
Oh, God, no!
我的天啊
Holy shit!
特里斯 别让他溜了
Treece, do not let him get away.
我找到他了 所有地面人员 开车追
I've got him. All ground vehicles, move in.
目标正沿着格兰特大街向东行驶
Target is now eastbound on Grant.
天啊 快做点什么
Oh, God! Do something!
这是什么…
What the…
真棒 又来了几个朋友 太爽了
Oh, yeah! We got more friends. Awesome.
不 不 不要
No, no, no! No, no!
不 你疯了吧
No! You're out of your mind!
不
No!
前面没有路了
That is a dead-end!
我们还有路
Not for us.
真棒
Yeah!
我要死了
I am going to die!
你不会死的
You are not going to die!
刚才真是太酷了 不骗你…
Whoa! That was pretty cool, actually. I'm not gonna lie…
抓到他了
I got him.
- 把他带回来 - 收到
- Bring him home. - Copy that.
真是太不可思议了
This is incredible.
你可真是能给我找事 埃迪
You have been a serious pain in the ass for me, Eddie.
好吧 你知道的
Well, you know,
我本来是想讨你欢心的
I aim to please.
眼睛 肺 还有胰脏
Eyes, lungs, pancreas.
都很好吃 可惜时间不多了
So many snacks, so little time.
旧金山警察 不许动
SFPD. Don't move!
从车上下来
Get off the car!
我的腿
My legs.
天啊 我的腿明明断了
Oh, my God, my legs were broken.
可现在却好好的
Now they're not broken.
这是怎么回事儿
What is happening?
你到底是什么东西
What the hell are you?
我叫毒液
I am Venom.
你的身体属于我
And you are mine.
你刚把别人的头给咬下来了
You bit somebody's head off.
我需要补充体力
Fuel in the tank.
听好了 埃迪
Listen carefully, Eddie.
不是你找到的我们
You did not find us.
是我们找上了你
We found you.
你现在就是我的坐骑
Think of yourself as my ride.
你要去哪
Where are you going?
我们要搭上德雷克的那艘火箭
We need Carlton Drake's rocket.
你还记得他吧
You remember him.
你是怎么知道这事儿的
How do you even know about that?
- 我无所不知 埃迪 - 是吗
- I know everything, Eddie. - You do?
- 我知道你的一切 - 怎么知道的
- Everything about you. - How?
我在你的脑子里
I am inside your head.
你就是个废物 埃迪
You are a loser, Eddie.
你还要再去吃其他人吗
Are you gonna eat anybody else?
很有可能
Most likely.
我的天啊
Oh, God.
我们来地球就是为了食物
That is why we are here.
乖乖合作 你才有可能活下去
Cooperate, and you might just survive.
这是我的条件
That is the deal.
晚上好 女士们 先生们
Good evening, ladies and gentlemen.
欢迎来到旧金山
Welcome to San Francisco.
为了您的安全 请不要离开座位…
For your safety and comfort, please remain seated…
（旧金山国际机场）
亲爱的 我快到家了
Hey, babe. I'm almost home.
- 埃迪在哪里 - 怎么了 发生了什么
- Where's Eddie? - Why? What's happening?
我拿到了埃迪的检查报告
I got Eddie's labs back,
比我想的还糟糕
and it's worse than I thought.
他的身体 肾脏 内分泌 全都不正常
His systems, renal, endocrine, they're behaving abnormally.
我从没见过这样的
I've never seen anything like it.
这是什么意思 丹 你想说什么
What does that mean, Dan? What are you telling me?
- 你得把他带过来 - 天啊
- You need to get him here. - My God.
- 埃迪·布洛克 请留言 - 该死
- Eddie Brock here. Leave a message. - Shit.
共生体离开斯克斯的时候 你在哪里
Where were you when it left Dr. Skirth's body?
- 他当时在哪儿 - 我在…
- Where was he? - I was…
这是一种高等生物
This is the higher life-form.
而你却看着它死掉
You stood by and watched while it died.
太自大了
The arrogance.
特里斯 听着 出了这档事儿
Treece, listen to me. After this,
我们现在不能冒险干掉布洛克
we can't risk killing Brock,
除非我们找到下一个合适的宿主
not until we find another suitable host.
我再也不想看见你这张脸了
I don't want to see you again
除非你把布洛克抓回来
unless you have Brock!
警官 发生了什么事 我需要进去
Officer, what's happening? I need to get in there.
- 这是我朋友的公寓 - 公寓已经被疏散了
- It's my friend's apartment. - Building's been evacuated.
你在这里不安全 女士
It's not safe for you to be here, madam.
又找到一个 比尔
Found another one, Bill.
别待在外面 回家吧
Get off the streets. Go home.
今晚城里到处是尸体
There's bodies all over the city tonight.
尸体
Bodies?
天啊 埃迪 你到底在哪儿
My God, Eddie, where are you?
安妮是谁 你的心跳加快了
Who is Anne? Your pulse has quickened.
这不关你的事
That is none of your goddamn business.
你所有的事都和我有关系 埃迪
Everything of yours is my business, Eddie.
你我之间没有秘密
We have no secrets.
是吗 那你一定知道我为什么要来这儿
Yeah? Well, then you know exactly why I'm going here
而不是先跟你去找火箭
before we get to your rocket, huh?
当然 我又不是不讲道理
Sure. I'm not unreasonable.
该死
Shit.
喂
Yeah?
埃迪 谢天谢地 你在哪儿 我得见你
Eddie. Thank God. Where are you? I need to see you.
不 不行 你不能见我
No, no, you can't see me.
埃迪 我得你告诉我你在哪 我过去接你
Eddie, I need you to tell me where you are. I'm coming to get you.
不 你绝对不能靠近我
No, you cannot come anywhere near me.
你现在不能靠近我
You cannot come near me right now.
理查德 嘿 理查德…
Richard. Hey, Richard…
- 不 - 埃迪
- No.- Eddie?
- 我得上去 - 你知道你不该来这里的 埃迪
- No, I gotta go up there. - You know you're not supposed to be here, Eddie.
我必须得上去 老兄
I got to get up there, man.
听着 我挺喜欢你的 兄弟 但你不能上去
Look, I got love for you, bro, but no can do.
没什么是不可能的
There's no such thing as can't.
我很抱歉 老兄
I'm sorry, man.
好 好吧…
Okay, okay… Uh…
你能把这个给他吗
Can you, uh, just give him this?
- 他得看看这上面的东西 - 埃迪 拜托
- He needs to see what's on it. - Eddie, please.
- 我需要这份工作 - 把他的脑袋咬下来吧
- I really need this job. - Let's eat his brains.
不 你不能碰他
No! You do not touch him!
- 他是我朋友 - 你怎么了
- He is my friend. - What's wrong with you?
- 他打了三份工就为了养家糊口 - 埃迪
- He works three jobs just so that he can support his family.- Eddie,
- 怎么了 - 我们要走了
- what's going on? - We're leaving.
- 「我们」 - 没错
- "We"? - Yeah.
- 你在说什么「我们」？- 离我远点
- What are you talking about, "we"? - Just stay back!
好了
Yeah.
该死
Shit.
你想上去吗
You want up?
你怎么不直接说呢
Well, why didn't you just say?
上面可真安静
It is peaceful up here.
我真的有点恐高
I'm not very good with heights.
你们的星球也没那么丑陋嘛
Your world is not so ugly after all.
可惜它就要被毁灭了
I'm almost sorry to see it end.
你什么意思
What does that mean?
你去哪儿了 你去哪儿了
Where'd you go? Where did you go?
有我在呢
I got us.
又来
Again?
你会害死我的
You're gonna get me killed.
你死了 我也会死
You die, I die.
对啊 但只要你想 你随时都能丢掉我的身体
Yeah, well, you can always just shed my carcass
然后换上一个其他人的
and exchange it for another one whenever you need.
我为什么要那么做
Why would I do that?
你的身体很好用 现在扔掉可惜了
You are far too good of a match to throw away so soon.
另外 我开始喜欢你了
Plus, I am starting to like you.
你我之间也没那么大的区别
You and I are not so different.
谢谢
Thank you.
（做正确的事 混蛋）
好了
Okay.
你要的证据在这儿
Here's your evidence.
跳吧
Jump.
怂货
Pussy.
举起手来
Hands!
趴到地上 快
On the ground! Now!
各位 你们这样做会后悔的 相信我
Guys, you do not want to do this. Trust me.
- 面罩 - 收到
- Mask! - Copy!
好吧 随便你们了
All right, have it your own way.
- 面罩 - 收到
- Mask! - Copy.
那是什么鬼东西
What the hell is that thing?
他还没死
He's not going down!
停火
Hold your fire!
闪光弹
Flares!
他在那 在那
He's there! He's there!
装弹
Reload!
有人看到他了吗
Anybody see him?
Does anyone have eyes on him?
切换到热成像 搜索目标中
Switching to thermal. Seeking target.
我看不到他了
I don't have eyes on him.
他在哪
Where is it?
闪光弹
Flash grenade!
快扔
Throw them!
闪光弹
Flash grenade!
他在屋顶
He's in the rafters!
上面
Above!
他在那
There he is!
闪开 快闪开
Move, move, move!
不 我们不能吃警察
No! We do not eat policemen!
安妮 安妮 等等
Annie! Annie, wait!
- 求你了 别走 - 那是什么鬼东西
- Wait, please. - Oh, what the hell is that?
那不是我 我被感染了
That's not me. I've been infected.
- 埃迪 到底怎么回事 - 他在我体内
- Eddie, what's happening? - He's inside me.
- 「他」 - 是的
- "He"? - Yes.
我知道这听起来很疯狂 但…
I know it sounds crazy, but…
你生病了
You're sick.
- 埃迪 你真的病了 - 不 我好害怕
- Eddie, you're really sick. - No, I am scared!
我需要帮助
And I need help.
去医院
Hospital.
现在就去
Right now.
我不能跟你一起去 太危险了
I can't go with you. It's not safe.
上车 埃迪
Get in the car, Eddie.
- 坐后面去 - 我喜欢她
- In the back. - I like her.
快上车
Get in.
我已经失控了
I'm out of control.
让丹再给你做个核磁共振
Dan just needs to do another MRI.
- 不做核磁共振 - 不 不做核磁共振
- No MRI. - No. No. No MRI.
什么 为什么
What? Why?
四千到六千赫兹的声音能要了我的命
Sound at 4, 000 to 6, 000 hertz is lethal.
核磁共振的声频会对他造成很大的伤害
Sound frequency in the MRI is really harmful for him.
什么 他怕声音 就像超人害怕氪石那样吗
What, so, sound is like his kryptonite?
- 不是所有的声音 - 还有火
- Not all sounds. - And fire.
火 他还怕火
Fire. And fire.
他在跟你说话吗
He's talking to you?
从没停过
Always.
- 你疼吗 - 不
- Are you in pain? - No.
实际上并没有什么感觉 只是觉得…
No, I don't feel anything, actually, apart from…
只是一直觉得很饿
I'm hungry all the time.
也觉得很伤心 不是吗 埃迪
And you feel sad, do you not, Eddie,
当你跟她在一起时
when you are with her?
从我脑子里滚出去 伙计
Get out of my head, man.
你从没道歉过
You never apologized.
错过这次机会 可能就没下次了
You might not live to get another chance.
安妮
Annie.
我只是想说 不论发生了什么
I just want to say that whatever happens,
我都真的 为我对你所做的一切 感到很抱歉
that I am truly sorry for whatever… And everything I have ever done to you.
我真的很抱歉
I am truly, truly sorry.
还有 我爱你
And that I love you.
埃迪…
Oh, Eddie…
现在真不是说这个的时候 先去医院 好吗
Now's really not the time. Let's just keep you alive, okay?
她可真好
Aw, that's nice.
我现在又湿又冷 我能穿下这个吗
You know, I'm really wet and cold. Can I, uh, wear this?
好 可以 你想穿什么都可以
Yeah, yeah, you can wear whatever you want.
谢谢
Thank you.
有人吗
Hello?
你在这儿做什么
What are you doing here?
你迷路了吗
Are you lost?
我没有迷路
I'm not lost.
谢谢你过来
Thanks for coming in.
埃迪 我很抱歉
Eddie, I'm sorry.
怎么了
What?
埃迪 我拿到了你的检验报告
Eddie, I got your labs back,
你的心脏已经严重衰竭了
and your heart has atrophied severely.
不要听他的话 我能治好你
Do not listen to him. I can fix it.
我不想让你来治我
I don't want you to fix it.
我能治好你
I can heal you.
你能治吗
Can you fix it?
不能 我从来没见过这样的东西
No. I've never seen anything like this before.
- 这个寄生虫 不管它是什么 - 「寄生虫」
- This parasite, whatever this is… - "Parasite"?
- 它在你体内吃着你的内脏 - 不是寄生虫 他不是
- It's eating you from the inside. - Not a parasite. He's not.
- 你在不断掏空他 - 不 她错了
- You're using him up. - No. She is wrong.
- 我们要带你去重症监护室 - 等等
- We need to get you to the ICU. - Wait. Shh!
- 我 埃迪 我要死了吗 - 不会的
- I, Eddie, am I dying? - No!
你会害死他的
You're killing him.
他们根本不明白这是怎么回事儿
They do not know what they are talking about.
听着 我们没有多少时间了
Listen, we don't have a lot of time…
- 天啊 - 我们赶紧离开这里
- Oh, God! - We have to get out of here.
- 住手 - 天啊 他要杀了你
- Stop! - Oh, God, he's killing you.
是我要杀你 真的很抱歉
I'm killing you. I'm so sorry.
不 别开那个
No! Don't do that!
你还好吗
Are you all right?
埃迪 抱歉 我必须把他赶出来
Eddie, I'm sorry. I had to get him out of you.
那是什么
What is that?
你想杀了我吗
You were killing me?
现在你再说「我们」 你再说
What happened to "we, " man? What happened to "we"?
对 看看你现在的样子
Yeah, look at you now, huh?
你现在也快死了
Now you're dying, too.
我们完了
We're done.
- 你现在要去哪 - 只要不是这里都好
- Where do you think you're going? - Anywhere other than here.
- 你不觉得我们还有点问题吗 - 等等
- You don't think we have a little problem on our hands? - Wait,
你不是要把这东西留在这吧
you're not gonna leave me here with this thing.
你要告诉我这到底是怎么回事吗
You want to tell me what the hell's going on?
我会的 你说得对
I do. And you're right.
我们确实需要聊聊
We do need to talk about it,
但我知道的也不比你多
but I don't know much more than you do.
我猜他应该是找不到别人帮忙了
I guess he had no one else to turn to.
他真让人捉摸不透
He's a very complicated man.
但是 丹 我保证
But, Dan, I promise,
我和埃迪之间真的没什么
there's nothing going on between me and Eddie.
我说的不是你和埃迪 安妮
I'm not talking about you and Eddie, Anne.
我是在说那个
I'm talking about that.
丹
Dan.
它去哪了
Where is it?
埃迪 埃迪…
Eddie, Eddie, Eddie.
你要杀就杀吧 反正我也快死了
You can kill me, because I'm dying anyway.
我才不会直接杀了你
I'm not just gonna kill you.
那样就不好玩了
That wouldn't be any fun.
不 不 不
No, no, no.
我要把你的舌头从嘴里拔出来
I'm gonna rip your tongue out of your face.
够了
Stop.
别弄脏我的实验室 出去 出去
You're bleeding all over my lab. Go. Go!
- 他在哪儿 - 我不知道
- Where is he? - I don't know.
知道吗 就算我知道 也不会告诉你
And you know what? Even if I did, I wouldn't tell you anyway.
我不相信你
I don't trust you,
你是个疯子
and you're insane.
- 太伤人了 - 抱歉
- That hurts. - Sorry.
这事我得详细写在日记里
Long journal entry about that tonight.
是你在犯蠢 布洛克 我没有疯
You're being dumb, Brock. I'm not insane.
真正疯狂的是如今人们的生活方式
What's insane is the way humans choose to live today.
想想看 我们做的只有索取 索取 再索取
Think about it. All we do is take, take, take.
不能再这样了
It can't go on.
我们把这颗星球带到了毁灭的边缘
We've brought the planet to the brink of extinction.
我们才是寄生虫 你就是例子
We're parasites. You're a good example.
想想看 你就只会索取
Think about it. All you do is take.
你抢走了我的共生体
You took my Symbiote.
你抨击一个想要拯救世界的伟人
You take potshots at a great man trying to get something done.
谁
Who?
你难道没从你最爱的人 最信任你的人身上
Didn't you take from the person you loved the most,
索取东西吗
who trusted you the most?
那才是疯了
That's insane.
我所开创的是一个全新的世界 一个新的物种
What I've initiated is a whole new world, a new species.
人类和共生体 结合起来
Man and Symbiote combined.
我来告诉你一件事 好吗
Let me tell you something, buddy. All right?
开诚布公的
Just man-to-man.
因为这几天我和这种生物
Because I have spent a significant amount of time,
一直待在一起
all right, with one of these creatures up my ass.
这一点儿都不好玩
It's not a lot of fun.
然后我发现
And then I find out,
他们一直以来都想要害死你
all along, that they're killing you.
我最后再问你一次
This is the last time I'm asking you.
- 我的共生体在哪 - 我不知道
- Where is my Symbiote? - I have no idea.
- 他在哪儿 - 我的天啊
- Where is he? - Oh, my God!
毒液在哪儿
Where's Venom?
这是我见过的最丑的东西
That is the ugliest-looking thing I have ever seen.
你知道的 布洛克
You know, Brock,
你对我来说没用了
I have no use for you.
特里斯 过来收拾你的烂摊子
Treece! Come and clean up your mess.
我去 他身体里也有一个
Whoa, he has one up his ass, too.
对你的朋友们 还有其他人
Your friends, the others, the others,
我很抱歉 我也很想让他们活下来
I apologize. I tried to keep them alive.
我们远不止这些 有上百万个
There are more of us. Millions more.
他们会遵循我的旨意
They will follow wherever I lead.
我们的旨意
Where we lead.
是的 「我们」
Yes, "we."
但首先 我们必须找到他们
But first, we must retrieve them.
我能搞定这件事
I can take care of that.
你要干嘛 要走到我累死为止吗
Yeah, what you gonna do, you gonna walk me to death?
闭嘴
Shut up.
没了你的朋友 你就没那么硬气了
Not so tough without your friend.
你妈妈不爱你的吗
Did your mama not love you?
该死的
God damn it!
我猜你当这方面的专家应该挣得不少
I guess it pays to be a specialist, huh?
你知道的 你杀不杀我不重要
You know, it doesn't matter if you kill me anyway,
因为这个世界上正在发生的事情
because there's something way bigger afoot
比你我都重要得多
in this world than you and me.
比我重要得多
Much bigger than me.
而且块头也比你大太多 太多了
And it's much, much bigger than you.
报应早晚会来的
Karma's a bitch.
我不相信报应
I don't believe in karma.
嗨 埃迪
Hi, Eddie.
不
Oh, no.
我刚把那家伙的脑袋咬下来了
I just bit that guy's head off.
我懂 我懂 我也体验过 这并不好玩
I know, I know. I've been there, too. It's not fun.
德雷克身上的是暴乱
The one with Drake is Riot.
谁是暴乱
Who's Riot?
暴乱就是你们所谓的团队领袖
Riot is what you would call a team leader.
他有个武器库
He has an arsenal of weapons.
德雷克也有他的共生体
Drake's got his own Symbiote.
- 他势不可挡 - 这下好了
- He is unstoppable. - Oh, great.
- 我们必须走了 - 去哪里 我们去哪里
- We have got to go! - Go where? Where we going?
- 我跟你一起去 - 不行
- Well, I'm coming with you. - No!
场面会很难看
It's going to get ugly.
她也能打得很凶残 相信我
Well, she can fight ugly. Trust me.
对 我可凶残了
Yeah, I can fight ugly.
今天不行
Not today.
简直胡扯
Oh, that's bullshit!
这次不是模拟发射
This is not a simulation.
飞行队还没准备好
Well, the flight team aren't prepped yet.
我来驾驶飞船
I'll be piloting the spacecraft.
- 你 - 没错 我
- You? - Yes, me.
还要多久
How long?
我们正在加载探测器以及运行诊断程序
We're loading the probe and running diagnostics.
不过 就算是全自动化的
But even fully automated,
你也不能独自驾驶飞船
you can't pilot that craft all alone.
我不是一个人
I'm not alone.
该死 刚刚发生了什么
God damn it! What the hell happened there?
- 我们丢下了安妮 - 这对她来说不安全
- We just left Annie. - It is not safe for her.
如果我们不阻止暴乱
If we do not stop Riot,
他会带着数以百万计的我的同类回到地球
he will come back here with millions more of my kind.
数百万
Millions?
怎么 你们要开走那艘火箭
What, you were gonna take the rocket,
再带着军队回来入侵地球吗
and you were gonna come back here with an invasion force?
然后你们打算做什么 你们要
Then what were you gonna do, you were gonna go
- 吞噬整个星球 - 没错
- feed on a whole planet? - Yes!
但现在不同了 埃迪
But it is different now, Eddie.
我已经决定留下来了
I have decided to stay.
在我的星球上 我也是个失败者 像你一样
On my planet, I am kind of a loser, like you.
- 但在这里 我们可以变得更强 - 你说什么
- But here, we could be more. - Excuse me?
我开始喜欢这里了
And I'm getting to like it here.
你现在喜欢我们了 是吗
Oh, you like us now, do you, huh?
但如果我们不阻止那个火箭
However, there will be nothing left to like
就没东西让我喜欢的了
if we do not stop that rocket.
我明白了
Oh, I see.
在灭顶之灾到来的时候
Right. When it comes to being completely annihilated,
就又是「我们」了
then it's back to "we."
的确是「我们」
It is "we."
不管你是否愿意 我们都会遭殃
Like it or not, it is going to take both of us.
行了 别扯淡了
Hey, come on, man. Cut the bullshit.
是什么让你改变主意的
What really made you change your mind?
你
You.
因为你 埃迪
You did, Eddie.
不要再检测了
Scrub diagnostics.
- 先生 - 你听不懂吗 启动发射程序
- Sir? - Did you hear me? Initiate the launch.
发射倒计时五分钟
T-minus five minutes to launch.
自动化进程已启动
Auto sequence has been initiated.
（中止协议 紧急制动）
该死
Oh, shit.
发射倒计时四分钟三十秒
T-minus four minutes, 30 seconds.
上帝啊 你能对付那家伙的 对吗
Oh, Jesus! You can take this guy, right?
你根本没见识过他有多厉害
He has got shit you have never seen.
什么意思 我们有多少胜算
What does that mean? What are our chances?
四舍五入一下 基本为零
Hmm. Pretty much zero.
不管了 我们去拯救地球
Oh, fuck it. Well, let's go save the planet.
倒计时四分钟
T-minus four minutes.
开始读取轨道飞行器配置文件
Initiate orbiter aerosurface profile.
毒液 上火箭
Venom. Get in the rocket.
不 我不会让你摧毁这个世界
No. We won't let you destroy this world.
那就去死吧
Then die.
- 天啊 - 跟你说了
- Holy shit! - Told you.
倒计时三分钟
T-minus three minutes.
你有一个强壮的宿主
You have a strong host.
但还是不够强壮
But not strong enough.
倒计时两分钟三十秒
T-minus two minutes, 30 seconds.
埃迪
Eddie.
德雷克 住手
Drake, stop!
跟你说了 我也能大杀特杀
Told you I could fight ugly.
倒计时一分钟
T-minus one minute.
你太迟了
You're too late.
这是下一个阶段…
This is the next stage…
你话太多了
You talk too much.
倒计时 三十秒
T-minus 30 seconds.
你什么都不是
You are nothing.
十秒
Ten seconds.
九…
Nine…
八…
Eight…
七…
Seven…
六…
Six…
五…
Five…
四…
Four…
三…
Three…
二…
Two…
一…
One…
发射
Liftoff.
叛徒
Traitor!
祝你生活愉快
Have a nice life.
再见了 埃迪
Goodbye, Eddie.
毒液 不
Venom, no!
谢谢你没放弃我 安妮 谢谢你救了我
Thanks for sticking by me, Annie. Thanks for saving me.
所以 经历了这些之后你感觉如何
So, how you feeling after all that?
好极了 很棒
I feel great. Awesome.
不过我在考虑起诉 你想帮我打官司吗
Yeah, I'm thinking of suing, though. You want to prosecute?
你运气真好 我决定无偿工作了
You're in luck. I've decided to work pro bono.
我要去做公设辩护律师了
I'm joining the public defenders' office.
你人真好 安妮
You're a good person, Annie.
你呢 你今后有什么打算
What about you? What are you gonna do?
电视台让我回去继续做节目
Uh, the network asked me to bring the show back,
他们想从德雷克的事开始
and they want to start with a piece on Drake.
真的吗 你怎么回复他们的
Oh, wow, really? So, what did you say?
我没多大兴趣
Uh, I'm not into it.
我想专心写几篇稿子
I want to concentrate on the written word.
我找好了一位特别好的采访对象
I scored the interview of a lifetime.
- 是吗 谁 - 你看了就知道了
- Oh, yeah? Who? - You're gonna have to read it.
我还得自己买报纸啊
Oh! Like everyone else.
是啊
Yeah.
毒液的事我很遗憾
Hey, I'm sorry about Venom.
嘿…
Hey, um…
你想谈谈那个吻吗
Do you want to talk about that kiss?
那个 那也算吻吗
Oh, that? You call that a kiss…
不 那是…
No, that was…
那是毒液的意思
Uh, that was your buddy's idea.
这样啊 好吧 这下清楚了
Oh, right. Well, that is good to know.
但感觉还是挺不错的
It did feel kind of great, though.
什么
What?
我是说 那种…
I mean, the…
- 那种力量吗 - 没错
- The power? - Yeah.
当它 你懂的…
When it's, you know…
- 在你体内的时候 - 我不是这意思
- Inside you? - You know what I mean.
好吧
Okay.
埃迪
Hey, Eddie?
我们还是不要告诉丹这件事情 好吗
We're not gonna tell Dan about this. Okay?
看看她 她完全不知道我们想把她追回来
Look at her. She has no idea we are going to get her back.
不 我不这样认为
No, I don't think so.
抱歉 你说什么
Sorry, what was that?
我们不会告诉丹
We're not gonna tell Dan.
埃迪 你有什么话想对我说吗
Eddie, is there something you want to tell me?
- 没有 - 你注定要和我们在一起 安妮
- Nope. - You belong with us, Annie.
埃迪 你确定吗
Eddie, are you sure?
上帝啊 看看这个
Good Lord, look at that.
看现在都几点了 我该走了
Look at the time. I have to go.
见到你真好
Hey, it's nice seeing you.
- 是啊 - 照顾好自己 好吗
- Yeah. - You take care, all right?
- 好的 你也保重 - 再见
- Yeah, you take care of yourself. - Bye.
嘿 别就这么放弃她了
Hey. Don't give up on her.
你们两个都是
Either of you.
我们不会的
We won't.
- 那个老头是谁 - 好吧
- Who is that guy? - Okay.
等等 这玩意看着很美味
Wait. This thing looks delicious.
我一点都不介意你留下来
I have absolutely no problem with you sticking around,
但既然你要长住 我们就得立些规矩了 好吗
but if you do, we're gonna have to have some ground rules, all right?
你不能动不动就开杀戒 想吃人就吃人
You cannot just go around eating anybody that you want to.
- 不能吃人吗 - 对 不能
- I cannot? - No, you cannot.
好了 我们得… 我们得反复重申这一点
All right, we need to… We need to reiterate this.
这世上有很多好人
There are good people in this world, a lot of them.
当然也有不少坏人
And then there are bad people.
你得学会辨别他们
You have to tell the difference.
规矩是 你只能接触
The deal is, you will only ever be allowed to touch,
伤害或是 有可能 有很大的可能
harm, hurt, possibly, very possibly,
吃掉那些非常非常坏的人
eat very, very bad people,
但是永远不能碰好人 明白吗
but never, ever, ever good people. All right?
好吧
Fine.
很好
Good.
但我要怎么辨别他们呢
But how does one tell the difference?
这太简单了
Well, it's super simple.
你只要… 你可以凭直觉 你可以意识到
I mean, you just have to… You can intuit it, you can sense it.
有时候你甚至能感受出来
Sometimes you can even feel it.
随你怎么说
Whatever you say.
我们现在能去吃点东西吗
But can we get something to eat now?
不然的话 你的肝脏现在看着真是鲜嫩多汁
Otherwise, your liver, it's starting to look really, really good and juicy.
好的 没问题 我知道这附近有个好地方
Yeah. Definitely. I know a place down here.
你好 陈太太
Hey, Mrs. C.
最近好吗 埃迪
How you doing, Eddie?
跟以前一样 没什么变化 你懂的
Aingt nothing changed but the weather. You know.
不
No.
那么 今晚您想吃什么宵夜呢
So, what culinary delights will tickle the pickle tonight?
炸薯球 还有巧克力
Tater tots and chocolate.
好 可以 没问题
Right. Okay, no problem.
该给钱了 陈
The payment's due, Chen.
求你了 我不能再这样了
Please. I can't keep doing this.
快点
Now.
- 那是个坏人 对吗 - 对
- Bad guy, right? - Yep.
你要是再敢来这家店
You come in here again…
不对 你要是再在这个城市的任何地方
In fact, you go anywhere in this city,
欺负无辜的市民
preying on innocent people,
我们会找到你
and we will find you
然后吃掉你的两只胳膊
and eat both your arms
- 还有你的两条腿 - 不 不要
- and then both of your legs. - No, no.
再把你的脸从脑袋上咬下来
And then we will eat your face right off your head.
你明白了吗
Do you understand?
- 求求你… - 没错
- Please… - Yes.
到时候你就会变成一个没胳膊没腿
So, you will be this armless, legless,
没脸的东西 懂吗
faceless thing, won't you,
滚在街上 就像风中的一坨屎
rolling down the street, like a turd in the wind?
- 你明白了吗 - 你到底是个什么东西
- Do you feel me? - What the hell are you?
我们是毒液
We are Venom.
- 我改主意了… - 求你了
- On second thought… - Please.
埃迪 那是什么
Eddie? What was that?
我长了个寄生虫
I have a parasite.
就是这样 晚安 陈太太
Yeah. Night, Mrs. Chen.
「寄生虫」
"Parasite"?
对 这是个爱称而已
Yeah. It's a term of endearment, that's all.
- 道歉 - 不要
- Apologize! - No.
- 快道歉 - 好吧 好吧
- Apologize! - All right, fine.
对不起
I'm sorry.
那你现在想做点什么
So, what do you want to do now?
在我看来 我们想做什么都可以
The way I see it, we can do whatever we want.
∮ 他们永远不会 ∮
∮ Not knowing with 'em. ∮
∮ 放慢脚步 ∮
∮ Never, gonna slow up in 'em. ∮
∮ 随时准备好被「它」附身吧 ∮
∮ Ready to snap any moment-um. ∮
∮ 是时候去袭击他们了 ∮
∮ Thinking it's time to go get em. ∮
∮ 他们分辨不清是谁袭击了自己 ∮
∮ They aingt gonna know what hit em. ∮
∮ 当他们看到 ∮
∮ When they get bitten with the. ∮
∮ 毒液 ∮
∮ Venom. ∮
∮ 感应到了 猛烈的波动 ∮
∮ I got that Adrenaline momentum. ∮
∮ 他们永远不会 ∮
∮ Not knowing with 'em. ∮
∮ 放慢脚步 ∮
∮ Never, gonna slow up in 'em. ∮
∮ 随时准备好被「它」附身吧 ∮
∮ Ready to snap any moment-um. ∮
∮ 是时候去袭击他们了 ∮
∮ Thinking it's time to go get em. ∮
∮ 他们分辨不清是谁袭击了自己 ∮
∮ They aingt gonna know what hit em. ∮
∮ 当他们看到 ∮
∮ When they get bitten with the. ∮
∮ 我说 敲打着 让那魔鬼进来 ∮
∮ I said knock knock, let the devil in. ∮
∮ 外星人 打电话想进家门 却不知道要等待多长时间 ∮
∮ Alien E-E-Eliott phone home ait 'no telling when this chokehold. ∮
∮ 这场游戏多会结束 我已经疯了 ∮
∮ On this game will end, I'm loco. ∮
∮ 就这样变成一个共生体 ∮
∮ Became a symbiote so. ∮
∮ 这样我的獠牙才能插入你的喉咙 ∮
∮ My fangs are in your throat, hoe. ∮
∮ 你正走近我的 ∮
∮ You're steppin with my. ∮
∮ 毒液 ∮
∮ Venom. ∮
∮ 拿着这支圆珠笔 ∮
∮ Put the ballpoint pen 'em. ∮
∮ 枪响 枪托 恶魔之眼 霰弹 ∮
∮ Gun cock, bump stock, devil eye, buck shot. ∮
∮ 把她绑到绞刑架上 ∮
∮ Tied her up to a garrote. ∮
∮ 系个双节 一把火烧掉 ∮
∮ Tie a couple knots, fired up and caught. ∮
∮ 就像红坦克 朋克摇滚 婊子像Yung Joc的歌曲一样下贱 ∮
∮ Fire juggerknot, punk rock, bitches going down like Yung Joc. ∮
∮ 涂满防晒霜 就像Doc让我制造点新闻出来 ∮
∮ Cause the Doc, put me on like sun block. ∮
∮ 为什么不呢 ∮
∮ Why the not. ∮
∮ 你只有这一次机会 ∮
∮ You only get one shot. ∮
∮ 不断受到唾骂直到司空见惯 ∮
∮ Ate shit 'til I can't taste it. ∮
∮ 全部烈酒猛地喝下去 ∮
∮ Chased it with straight liquor. ∮
∮ 再来点油漆稀释剂 直到我头晕目眩 ∮
∮ Then paint thinner then drank till I faint. ∮
∮ 然后头痛欲裂的醒来 ∮
∮ And I wait with a headache and I take anything in. ∮
∮ 任何矩形的东西我都能接受 ∮
∮ Rectuangular shape, then I wait. ∮
∮ 去面对管束着我的魔鬼 ∮
∮ And I take anthing in rectangular shape. ∮
∮ 因为他们在追我 但我是你的一部分 ∮
∮ Cause they're chasing me but I'm part of you. ∮
∮ 想逃跑是不可能的 ∮
∮ So escaping me is impossible. ∮
∮ 我就长在你的身体里 ∮
∮ I'ma latch on you like a. ∮
∮ 就像一个寄生虫 也许还毁了你父母的生活 ∮
∮ Parasite, and I probably ruined your parents life. ∮
∮ 还有你的童年 ∮
∮ And your childhood too. ∮
∮ 因为如果你们在成长途中听着我的的音乐 ∮
∮ Cause if I'm the music yall grew up. ∮
∮ 我要为你们这些反应迟钝的傻瓜们负责 ∮
∮ I'm responsible for you retarded fools. ∮
∮ 我就是把你们全家都吓个半死的超级大坏蛋 ∮
∮ I'm the supervillain, dad and mom were losing their marbles to. ∮
∮ 你很惊讶吗 埃迪·布洛克就是你 ∮
∮ You marvel that, Eddie Brock is you. ∮
∮ 而我就是你的外体 请叫我 ∮
∮ And I'm the suit, so call me. ∮
∮ 毒液 ∮
∮ Venom. ∮
∮ 感应到了 猛烈的波动 ∮
∮ I got that Adrenaline momentum. ∮
∮ 他们永远不会 ∮
∮ Not knowing with 'em. ∮
∮ 放慢脚步 ∮
∮ Never, gonna slow up in 'em. ∮
∮ 随时准备好被「它」附身吧 ∮
∮ Ready to snap any moment-um. ∮
∮ 是时候去袭击他们了 ∮
∮ Thinking it's time to go get em. ∮
∮ 他们分辨不清是谁袭击了自己 ∮
∮ They aingt gonna know what hit em. ∮
∮ 当他们看到 ∮
∮ When they get bitten with the. ∮
∮ 毒液 ∮
∮ Venom. ∮
∮ 感应到了 猛烈的波动 ∮
∮ I got that Adrenaline momentum. ∮
∮ 他们永远不会 ∮
∮ Not knowing with 'em. ∮
∮ 放慢脚步 ∮
∮ Never, gonna slow up in 'em. ∮
∮ 随时准备好被「它」附身吧 ∮
∮ Ready to snap any moment-um. ∮
∮ 是时候去袭击他们了 ∮
∮ Thinking it's time to go get em. ∮
∮ 他们分辨不清是谁袭击了自己 ∮
∮ They aingt gonna know what hit em. ∮
∮ 当他们看到 ∮
∮ When they get bitten with the. ∮
∮ 毒液 ∮
∮ Venom. ∮
∮ 感应到了 猛烈的波动 ∮
∮ I got that Adrenaline momentum. ∮
∮ 他们永远不会 ∮
∮ Not knowing with 'em. ∮
∮ 放慢脚步 ∮
∮ Never, gonna slow up in 'em. ∮
∮ 随时准备好被「它」附身吧 ∮
∮ Ready to snap any moment-um. ∮
∮ 是时候去袭击他们了 ∮
∮ Thinking it's time to go get em. ∮
∮ 他们分辨不清是谁袭击了自己 ∮
∮ They aingt gonna know what hit em. ∮
∮ 当他们看到 ∮
∮ When they get bitten with the. ∮
（圣昆廷监狱））
我需要你保持安静
I need you to stay quiet.
这是我的事 不是我们的事
This is a "me" thing. It is not a "we" thing.
明白了吗
You got that?
好吧 但你快点
Fine, but make it quick.
打开五号牢房
Open on five.
开门
Go. Opening up.
要我说 就不该听他的话
You ask me, they're dumb to let him call the shots.
要是他提出来叫你采访他
Second he asked for you to interview him,
我会马上叫他闭嘴
I'd have shut that shit down.
是啊 你知道联调局的德行 他们就是要利用
Oh, yeah, you know the FBI. They're just taking advantage
他唯一一次跟别人交流的机会
of the one and only time he'll ever speak to anyone.
他们希望我能帮他们指认更多的尸体
They're hoping that I might help them identify some additional bodies.
联调局压根不会亲自上阵
FBI don't work up close and personal with him.
你要是不懂规矩 你就是下一具要指认的尸体了
The FBI will have to identify you, if you don't follow the rules.
嘿 红毛 有人来看你了
Hey, Red! I got a visitor for you.
（欢迎你 埃迪）
- 你好 埃迪 - 嗨
- Hi, Eddie. - Hey.
我们先不谈那些可怕的连环杀人的事 你不介意吧
Do you mind if we forego the whole creepy serial killer thing here?
好 我没意见
Sure, it's good with me.
如果你想听 我也可以聊
I mean, I can turn it on if you want.
我可以给你讲讲
I can talk about
动脉鲜血四溅产生的艺术效果
the Dadaist patterns of arterial spray.
这点我相信
I bet you can.
灯太暗了 我看不清你 埃迪
Tough to see you in this light, Eddie.
过来点儿
Come on over.
好吧
All right.
我过来了
I'm here.
我肯定会出去的 等我出去之后
When I get out of here, and I will,
会有一场屠杀
there's gonna be carnage.
抱歉 帕克先生
I'm sorry, Mr. Parker.
我本想完成你交代的事
I want to do what you asked.
我尽力了
I really do.
但是…
But…
对不起
I'm sorry.
没有你我真的做不到
I can't do this without you.
嘿 孩子
Hey, kid…
这是…
What was… Whoa!
什么
What?
Huh?
不
No.
你是谁
Who are you?
你在那儿干什么
What are you doing over there?
我们是警察 不许动
Freeze! PDNY.
小子 不许动
Kid, freeze!
你这是在逗我吗
You're kidding me right now?
孩子 放下他
Hey, kid. Drop the body.
谁来让火车停下
Somebody stop that train!
抱歉
Sorry.
看起来是一个打扮的像蜘蛛侠的小孩
…looks like a child dressed like Spider-Man,
拖着一具流浪汉的尸体
dragging a homeless corpse
跟在火车后面
behind a train.
- 你是谁 - 你是谁
- Who are you? - Who are you?
你刚才为什么要杀我
Why are you trying to kill me?
我没有 我是在救你
I'm not. I'm trying to save you.
嘿 你们其实可以绕过去
Hey, maybe you guys can go around?
好吧 谢谢 纽约
All right. Thanks, New York.